I guess they deserve credit for
arriving earlier than expected.
So, they took up a river-defense formation?
If we're both the same strength,
the first side to attack loses.
We'll be staring at each other for a while.
Brother, why not have the men
test the river's depth?
I know how deep the Kuriri river is.
The river's swollen from the rain now,
so it's about chest high...
A squad is leaving the formation.
Solork's platoon?
There's a shallow spot upriver.
He's planning to send his men around
and strike us from behind.
Warrant Officer Yatorishino!
Yes, sir.
Your squad is to head upriver to intercept.
Isn't it risky to split up our forces now?
There's a river between us.
As long as we don't make the first move,
we have the advantage.
The enemy chose this location.
Don't you think it's too naive
to assume it would help us?
Shut up!
Obey your superior officer's orders!
These guys are child's play
for you, aren't they, Ikta?
Okay, sadistic hottie.
Get ready.
Watchdogs of the Spirit Tree
Warrant Officer, should we really stop
instead of heading to the objective?
If they're here, we can intercept them,
and if they're not, we can get back
to the main force in short order.
Right now, we should wait
for the scout report.
No sign of the enemy unit.
Was it a trap?
Let's tell Warrant Officer Yatorishino!
What?
They just sent scouts, huh?
But, if nothing else,
we've lured Yatori-san as far away
from their main unit as possible.
That's the signal.
All troops, prepare to fire!
Okay!
All forces, charge!
Make a bridge in the river?
Yup. An underwater bridge.
This is called an Isu tree.
It's very heavy and sturdy.
We'll sink it in the water.
The water's muddy,
so they won't be able to see it.
Basically, we'll be the only ones to know
that the river isn't protecting anyone.
It can't be that shallow!
Brother, your orders.
F-Fire! Open fire!
Just as the Warrant Officer said,
the enemy is unable to
handle this sudden attack.
And we have three platoons,
against their two.
Get out of the way if you're dead!
Retreat!
Keep firing as you retreat!
Gotcha!
Looks like I made it in time!
Yatori's here already?
Okay, everyone! Fighting time's over!
Retreat!
We're changing position!
Defend our retreating allies and
get to the northern forest!
Two Hours After the Battle
I'm back, Ikkun.
From the look of it, things went well.
Yeah, I guess it was a success.
And don't call me Ikkun!
Hey, Matthew.
You still alive?
Yeah.
Somehow.
We took out a lot of their men,
so do you think they'll surrender?
With the sadistic hottie running things,
he might make them fight to the last man.
Unless we can kill him.
Let's change our formation.
Haro, tend to the wounded.
Y-You noticed us here?
Okay, since it looks like
the battle's over...
Excuse us.
What was the plan if the enemy
checked the depth of the river first?
He knows this training area so well
that the odds he'd do that were low.
Well, if he'd tried,
our air rifles would have chased them off.
I'll get the survivors together.
Yeah, thanks.
Looks like you got him good, Solork.
You should've seen the look on his face.
We're still doing our training exercise.
Get lost, please, Princess.
Damn it!
Yatorishino!
You should have been there sooner!
I'm sorry.
If you've got a squad that can move faster,
I'd like to see it.
Brother.
What's our next move?
They should be coming for us.
We'll ambush them on the road to the west,
and then catch them in a pincer attack!
Enjoy your victory while
you can, Ikta Solork!
I'll punch that smug grin
right off your stupid face!
He's probably saying something like that
and burning for revenge right now.
That said, we're not pursuing.
How do we win, then?
Suya, first get rid of the idea
that we're chasing the enemy.
Chasing someone is tiring,
and being chased is mentally exhausting.
But making someone chase you can be fun.
War is just like love that way.
One Hour Later
What's going on?
Do they not plan on actually fighting?
R-Reporting in!
The enemy's three platoons
have deployed their troops
to seal the north exit of the forest!
What are they playing at?
They got us.
They've cut off our escape route, Captain.
At some point, we have to use the
north exit to get to the Central Base.
If they've got the exit sealed
at the end of the mock battle,
we'll lose because we won't
even be able to get home.
So they'll just win by default?
We're heading to the northern exit!
There they are.
Okay, all units,
make it look like you're ready to fire.
But in fact, be ready to charge.
Don't get too far ahead,
and be sure to work with
the person next to you.
Compared to the value of teamwork,
the honor of being the first
inside their lines is nothing.
Come on, line up!
Brother, we're charging?
Yeah.
The boundary line of the
combat zone is behind them.
If even a single one of
them crosses that line,
they lose for breaking the rules!
Listen up, men.
Even if you die,
don't fall down immediately.
Pretend you didn't notice and push them back!
Now that's against the rules...
Shh!
Okay, all forces, charge!
Torway, you bastard!
All troops, charge!
Lieutenant Sushuraf,
the Captain has fallen.
Take command.
Very well.
There's no way to win this battle.
We'll break through and escape!
Open us a path, Yatorishino!
Understood!
All troops, charge!
I can't believe it.
Does this mean we...
We couldn't wipe them out,
but you could say we won, yeah.
We really...
Okay, everyone, quiet down.
Now it's lecture time for my beloved men.
Private First Class Gwemp.
Private First Class Aigi.
Private Bio.
Corporal Tobai.
Come up to the front.
You guys,
I clearly warned you beforehand,
and you still charged too far ahead.
What the hell was that?
Ikta's platoon doesn't need heroes.
Instead of trying to win one-on-three,
come up with a way to fight three-on-one.
That's the scientific way of thinking.
"Scientific?"
What does that mean?
Logical, streamlined, and efficient.
And as a result,
it allows you to be very lazy.
It's a wonderful way to think.
People started to grow crops because
going hunting without knowing if
you'd catch anything was a pain.
People dug wells because going
all the way to the river was a pain.
Laziness is the mother of human progress.
Of course, war is no different.
If you can slack off during a war,
you're doing it right.
So follow me, Ikta Solork.
Ikta Solork's men fight easy, and win easy.
Hooray for laziness!
Hooray for sloth!
Everyone who follows me
gets an easy life.
Ikta Solork...
Ikta Solork! Ikta Solork!
H-Huh?
What's going on?
Huh?
We take our eyes off Ikkun for a second,
and he's suddenly really popular.
No, it happened while I had my eyes on him.
I was moved, and I have no idea why.
I may have spread it on a little too thick.
Okay, everyone, quiet.
I get it. I get it.
Thank you! Thank you!
Torway.
What?
Did our war of attrition work?
I think we were able to wait for
the best chance we could have gotten.
I see.
Good.
Oh, I saw Princess Chamille while
I was hiding in the forest.
She was hurrying to the west
with her royal guards.
She probably went to see Yatori, right?
That's totally the wrong direction, Matthew.
The princess should know that.
She should have no reason to head west.
Where...
Where is Solork?
You bastard!
Princess, flee!
So Solork's injury was a lure to draw me out?
Captain Ison Ho.
Why are you doing this?
Solork...
The mock battle is about to end.
Shall we send up the surrender signal?
Surrender?
Why would we do that?
Captain, Lieutenant Sushuraf
is in charge now.
I'm not letting that happen.
I'll never surrender!
Refusing will simply damage
your own reputation,
as the commander who didn't
know when to give up.
If you surrender now, you can still say
you succeeded in your final retreat.
Make the right decision, sir.
Sound instead of light
for their communications?
"West... The Princess."
Yatorishino Igsem and her eight
soldiers will head to the west.
That signal?
Yes.
It seems something has happened.
Take the remaining two from my squad.
You saved my older brother
during the first battle.
I'm grateful for that.
If we can get to the road,
the carriage will be waiting for us.
And then the mission will be complete.
That's right.
We're almost done.
If it hurts to look at
the princess, then don't.
You knew what you were in for at the start.
Yes, sir.
They whittled down the tip
instead of using an arrowhead?
A light troop would've started
by trying to blind us.
And you can't be medics.
Which means you're a fire troop
that's low on equipment.
Correct, Warrant Officer Yatorishino Igsem?
Now, fire your second round.
Then we'll...
Know where we are,
Captain Ison Ho?
Don't move.
Try anything, and your head
will hit the ground.
Very well.
All forces, shoot her now.
You got lucky.
It seems they don't want you dead.
I'd thought I'd trained them more thoroughly.
Princess...
Yatori?
Where am I?
Princess, are you hurt?
Let me go!
Please calm down.
I'll save you now.
But... But...
Solork is...
Ikta will be here soon.
Release the princess.
I will tell you our motive.
Motive?
The reason we abandoned
all our pride as soldiers
and resorted to committing this crime.
We are all students of
Lieutenant General Hazaf Rikan.
Lieutenant General Rikan...
He was a talented commander.
However, he died during the
battle at the Eastern Garrison.
Then, what you're after...
That's right, Princess.
We will avenge our teacher,
who died to cover up a political failure,
with your worthless life!
Princess, please...
I don't like raising my voice,
but once in a while, it's worth it.
Watch our surroundings.
Stop it!
Fire Spirit.
Move, and your master dies.
Let me go!
Stop it! Let Yatori go!
P-Princess...
Princess, are you safe?
I'm glad...
Y-Yatori...
Yatori.
Yatori-san...
Huh? My hands won't let go of my sword...
Man, you sure made a mess again.
I won't be able to eat tomatoes for a while.
Ikta...
Hey, Yatori.
You may already know this,
but you're extremely red right now.
I don't mind being red,
but I don't like the way my
body smells like metal.
Smells?
That's not got nothing with you being red.
It's because you're holding these big
hunks of metal in your hands, right?
No matter what happens,
don't forget that I'm your left hand!
Okay, got them out.
Good work.
Thank you.
But, you know...
I might be a little tired.
You always work too hard.
Like I keep telling you,
you need to slack off more.
May I ask for an explanation,
Captain Ison Ho?
Th-They said they were students
of Lieutenant General Rikan.
I understand completely,
and I don't feel like condemning you.
Honestly, you could have
asked me to join you.
Ikta!
Your tactics are somehow similar
to Lieutenant General Rikan...
No, they resemble the tactics
of his teacher, Bada Sankrei.
Is that a coincidence?
That's...
Ikkun.
It's over.
Yeah.
It's been a tiring couple of days.
Our little camping trip
in Kioka was a lot easier.
Hey, Princess.
Looks like you've got a colorful new dress.
Or did you just spill a lot of
tomato sauce on yourself?
It's hard to tell.
By the way, this is a secret,
but you're really red right now.
Ikta...
Wh-Why?
Solork! Solork, you jerk!
Imperial Year 906, June.
Very few know of this "parting gift"
from Lieutenant General Hazaf Rikan.
But it's also true that those involved
were left with mental scars
that would never fade.
Next Time: Two Are One.
Two Are One